<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Homes on Damaris Zurell research</title>
    <link>https://damariszurell.github.io/home/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Homes on Damaris Zurell research</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-uk</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; Damaris Zurell</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://damariszurell.github.io/home/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://damariszurell.github.io/home/hero/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://damariszurell.github.io/home/hero/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://damariszurell.github.io/home/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://damariszurell.github.io/home/about/</guid>
      <description>Understanding biodiversity in a changing world
I explore how species and communities respond to environmental change across spatial and temporal scales — from individual fitness to global distribution patterns. My research integrates principles from theoretical ecology and conservation with advanced statistical and mechanistic modelling to understand why species are where they are, how they got there, and how they will persist in the future.
In my group, we develop and test cutting-edge biodiversity models by integrating ecological theory, conservation perspectives, and large-scale data with scenarios of global change.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>People</title>
      <link>https://damariszurell.github.io/home/people/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://damariszurell.github.io/home/people/</guid>
      <description>For opportunities to join the lab, please have a look here.
Group leader:
 Damaris Zurell (PhD) - Professor of Ecology &amp;amp; Macroecology at University of Potsdam  Administrative assistant:
 Silke Brandt  Scientific programmers:
 Robert Hering (MSc) - ecological data analyst Jette Wolff (PhD) - ecological modeller and scientific programmer  Senior &amp;amp; Postdoctoral researchers:
 Maira Cardoso (PhD) - macroecology, biodiversity conservation, bird diversity, global change Mariana Chiuffo (PhD) - Humboldt fellow, plant community ecology, species interactions, invasion biology Bettina Ohse (PhD) - Individual postdoc project, functional biodiversity, forest disturbances Coline Royaux (PhD) - Postdoc within University Focus Area Individual-based global change ecology, freshwater diversity from genes to communities, ecological coupling, dispersal Patricia Singh (PhD) - Individual postdoc project, peatland ecology, range shifts, ecological forecasting Juliane Wolter (PhD) - Individual postdoc project, paleoecology, effects of Arctic vegetation changes on carbon dynamics  Doctoral researchers:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Projects</title>
      <link>https://damariszurell.github.io/home/projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://damariszurell.github.io/home/projects/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Publications</title>
      <link>https://damariszurell.github.io/home/publications/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://damariszurell.github.io/home/publications/</guid>
      <description>You can find a full list of my publications here.
My ResearcherID is E-2439-2012. You can also find me on ResearchGate and GoogleScholar.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Teaching</title>
      <link>https://damariszurell.github.io/home/teaching/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://damariszurell.github.io/home/teaching/</guid>
      <description>Current teaching:
 BSc course &amp;ldquo;Introduction to scientific working in ecology&amp;rdquo;, Bachelor programme Bioscience, Univ. Potsdam MSc course &amp;ldquo;R preparatory course&amp;rdquo;, Master programme &amp;ldquo;Ecology, Evolution and Conservation&amp;rdquo;, Univ. Potsdam. R practicals for block course provided online MSc module &amp;ldquo;Experimental design and data analysis&amp;rdquo;, Master programme &amp;ldquo;Ecology, Evolution and Conservation&amp;rdquo;, Univ. Potsdam MSc module &amp;ldquo;Macroecology and global change&amp;rdquo;, Master programme &amp;ldquo;Ecology, Evolution and Conservation&amp;rdquo;, Univ. Potsdam. R practicals on macroecological analyses and species distribution modelling provided online MSc module &amp;ldquo;Quantitative conservation biogeography&amp;rdquo;, Master programme &amp;ldquo;Ecology, Evolution and Conservation&amp;rdquo;, Univ.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Downloads</title>
      <link>https://damariszurell.github.io/home/downloads/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://damariszurell.github.io/home/downloads/</guid>
      <description>You can download some of my codes from my github site.
Latest software developments in my team include:
 an R package for the RangeShifter platform. More info under https://rangeshifter.github.io a Shiny web app introducing and facilitating the usage of the ODMAP protocol for reporting SDM. Check out here: odmap.wsl.ch  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact</title>
      <link>https://damariszurell.github.io/home/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://damariszurell.github.io/home/contact/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>